Guide to the Robert Flynn Papers
The Wittliff Collections
Robert Flynn Papers
1950-1971
The Wittliff Collections
Flynn, Robert, 1932-
SWWC.023
3 Linear Feet
6 boxes
The collection consist of a script, programs, drafts, notes, photographs, articles, military documents and correspondence and span fom 1950-1971.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Flynn, 1989-1993.
Biographical Notes
Robert Flynn was born April 12, 1932, in Chillicothe, Texas. He graduated with a degree in drama from Baylor University in 1954. After teaching speech and drama for two years at Gardner-Webb College in North Carolina, Flynn returned to Baylor as an assistant professor in the Drama Department. When the Baptist university closed down the 1962 production of Long Days Journey Into Night, Flynn followed the entire drama faculty, headed by department chair Paul Baker, to Trinity University, where Flynn continues to hold a position in the English Department as writer-in-residence.
In 1964, Flynn adapted William Faulkner's As I Lay Dying to the stage in a play entitled Journey to Jefferson. The Dallas Theater Center Production directed by Paul Baker won a Special Jury Award at the Theater of Nations in Paris in 1964. In 1967, Knopf published Flynn's first novel, North to Yesterday, a hilarious trail driving adventure that is "at the same time... an ungentle satire on the foolishness of those who live in the past as well as the blindness of those who turn their backs on it."(Garfield 38). This was followed by two other works published by Knopf In the House of the Lord (1969), The Sounds of Rescue, the Signs of Hope (1970), and by Wanderer Springs (1987), published by Texas Christian University Press. Flynn has published two collections of short stories, Seasonal Rain (1986), and Living with the Hyenas (1995).
Flynn had temporarily dropped out of college to serve two years with the Marines during the Korean War. In 1970 after many years in academia, he sought out a position as a war correspondent to Vietnam, eventually getting his credentials through True Magazine. Flynn spent two months in Vietnam and was profoundly affected by the experience. He ultimately wrote a memoir, A Personal War in Vietnam, published in 1989 and a novel, The Last Klick, published in 1994.
Two stories in Seasonal Rain were winners in the NEA/PEN Syndicated Fiction Project. Wanderer Springs won a Spur Award from Western Writers of America and North to Yesterday won a Western Heritage Wrangler Award from the National Cowboy Hall of Fame.
Bibliography: Garfield, Brian, Saturday Evening Post, July 22, 1967: 38.
Scope and Contents
The Robert Flynn papers consist of a script, programs, drafts, notes, photographs, articles, military documents and correspondence. A copy of Flynn's script Journey to Jefferson is included along with programs from the 1964 European tour of the play. There is a typescript of Flynn's first novel, North to Yesterday, with related notes and letters from the publisher covering editor's comments, suggestions for revision, title changes, foreign publication, sales and reviews. Also present are galleys and plate proofs from In the House of the Lord. Flynn had served as a Marine in Korea and he covered Vietnam in 1971 for True Magazine. This collection contains material from his tour, including a guide to Vietnam and a pamphlet on the operation of an M16 rifle; combat photographs; Flynn's marine I.D. and dogtag, his True Magazine press I. D. cards and ration card; Vietnamese money, telegrams, newsletters, reports, Flynn's handwritten notes and a camouflage uniform.
Dramatists; Authors, American -- 20th century; American journalists; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Flynn, Robert, 1932-
- Plays, 1960-1967
  Series Description
  This series is comprised of material relating to Flynn's play Journey to Jefferson. Documents include a typescript draft of the play and various play programs.
  - Journey to Jefferson, 1960-1967
    - Signed typescript, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Play programs, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Novels, 1967-1989
  This series contains documents pertaining to Flynn's novels North to Yesterday, In the House of Our Lord, and The Last Klick. Also included in this series are materials related to Flynn's published memoir A Personal War in Vietnam. Included are various draft typescripts, galleys, and plate proofs.
  - North to Yesterday, 1965-1967
    - Notes (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Typescript (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
    - Correspondence from Knopf Publishers, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Copy edited draft, November 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Title pages (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - Galleys (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
    - Plate proofs (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Proof of excerpt for Saturday Evening Post, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - In the House of Our Lord, 1969
    - Correspondence from Knopf Publishers (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Typescript version titled In the Midst of Days (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Typescript version titled Days of Our Fathers (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Galleys (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Plate Proofs (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - A Personal War in Vietnam, 1989
    - Annotated typescript (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Page proofs (Box 4, Folder 5, Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - The Last Klick, 1988-1994
    - Annotated typescript (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    - Annotated typescript, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Annotated typescript, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Various annotated typescript pages (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Vietnam War Coverage for True Magazine, 1967-1989
  Included in this series are materials from Flynn's tenure as a war correspondent for True magazine. This series is comprised of handwritten notes, clippings, military records, Vietnamese money, and other related ephemera.
  - Card with legend for military signals for combat zone hazards, combat leaders checklist booklet, operation and maintenance booklet for M16AI rifle, pocket guide to Vietnam, Vietnamese flyer, and envelope from Department of the Army (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 61 black and white and 16 color photographs of Vietnam, soldiers, and Vietnamese citizens and envelope from First Sargeant C.E. Buckley (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Proofs of 1st Battalion, 5th Marines, 1st Marine Division newsletters, Tourane 1535 Da Nang fact sheet (1950), miscellaneous military newsletters, numerous handwritten notes, receipts and bills from Hotel Caravelle, Saigon, clippings The Northern Log, historical briefs of military units, award application for James W. Carter, and boarding pass for 834th division tactical airlift and camouflage uniform., 1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dog tag for Robert Flynn, Vietnamese coinage and paper money, and ration card, various identification cards for Robert Flynn, check-in card for Hotel Caravelle in Saigon, MACV morning release for January 5, 1971, photocopies of clippings, map of military camp, various typescripts and notes, Marines brochure, three black and white photographs of military actions, and accompanying text for press releases (Box 6, Folder 6)